This is Lorelei Martins.
She's a confederate
of the serial killer Red John.
Nineteen days ago she disappeared
from Sacramento County Jail.
She was last seen in Wing B
Cell 826 at three-thirty PM.
What does this have to do with me?
Someone drove her out of the jail.
The only vehicles that entered
the facility near that time
were prisoner transport vehicles.
You were driving one of them.
Was it you?
No.
Hey.
Was it you?
No, all right?
- What's wrong with you?
- You can go. Thank you.
Morning, Lisbon.
Now?
Well, I... I have another driver coming in.
Yeah. Okay.
Fine. I'll be right there.
Hey, Boss.
Victim's a community security guard.
Casey Borras.
Shot twice, one in the arm
one in the chest.
Happened about an hour ago.
We've notified his family.
His weapon was out?
Was he responding to a call?
No. Security company
says he was on patrol.
Could've come across
a robbery or home invasion.
Sac PD's doing door-to-doors.
Jane? Thoughts?
Uh, no.
Gather the neighbors.
I was in the den checking my Facebook
messages when I heard the shots.
And, there were, like, two of them.
Did you see anything?
No. By the time I came outside
whoever did this was gone.
- And what about you, sir?
- No, I just got home about ten minutes ago.
Did anybody see any suspicious
people or vehicles?
Anything at all?
- What's going on with you?
- What?
Everyone else here wants to help.
You just wanna get out of here.
- No, I don't.
- Can't keep your eyes off your phone.
- What's your name?
- Isaac. Isaac Goodwin.
- Which house is yours?
- I don't live in this neighborhood.
My brother and his wife do.
Right over there.
Where are they?
Out of town.
I'm collecting their mail.
No, you're not.
Excuse me?
You... You're in high finance. You're
a banker, a hedge fund manager, yes?
- Yes.
- You don't do favors for people
unless there's something in it for you.
- That's not true.
- Is the mailbox empty or full?
- I, uh...
- Say no more.
Go on.
I don't know what you think
you're gonna find.
Well, how about evidence of a struggle?
It must be the movers.
Marcus and Pella
just got some new furniture.
Remind me not to hire them.
Where are your brother and his wife now?
I don't know.
Sometimes they just leave town.
They're spontaneous.
Where is he going?
I thought you stopped by to collect the mail.
I got hungry.
Eh, hungry enough for two, it seems.
- What's going on?
- Nothing.
We're not leaving until you tell us
what happened.
No. Don't answer that.
- Why not?
- Just don't. Give it to me.
- Well, tell me.
- I can't.
- Well, if you don't, I'm gonna answer it.
- Don't!
- He told me not to involve the police.
- Who did?
The kidnapper.
He took Marcus and Pella and he told me
he'd kill them if I involved the police.
Better answer it, then.
- Hello?
- "You alone?"
- Yes.
- "Tell me, what are you wearing?"
Hi, how are you doing? It's me.
Yeah.
Okay.
We can just talk now... kidnappers.
The River Park neighborhood
of Sacramento
where local security guard...
All right, we're dealing
with a kidnapping.
The victims are Pella
and Marcus Goodwin.
They were taken about 90 minutes ago.
It looks like a security guard
came across the scene
tried to intervene, and was shot.
So we find the kidnapper
we've got the killer.
But right now our priority is
getting the Goodwins back safely.
Has the kidnapper made contact?
He emailed the brother around
the time of abduction.
Isaac Goodwin came to the house
to verify it was true.
- What about a ransom demand?
- Five million dollars.
They got that kind of money?
Isaac says Marcus is the chief designer
at a communication software firm.
He's got big government contracts
and holds major patents.
So, yes, he's got the money.
The kidnapper's supposed
to be in touch within the hour.
Van Pelt's in the kitchen setting up.
I'll put out a BOLO.
Rigsby, I need you to check all
the security camera footage in the area.
Traffic lights, residential, anything that
can put an ID on our suspect.
The clock's ticking, let's move.
- Yes, boss.
What now?
Great system, huh?
Could you turn that off?
Sure, sure, hang on a second.
Uh...
It's a little harder than it looks.
We're gonna need to put
together the ransom.
Can you help with that?
Yes. I'm Marcus' business manager.
Why the hesitation?
Well, it's five million dollars.
I'm not just gonna go to the bank
and then hand it over to them.
I mean, there has to be
a negotiation first.
Which we will run.
And we're gonna need your phone.
The kidnapper contacted you.
He'll probably do so again.
Okay, maybe I wasn't clear before.
If he knows that you guys are involved
then Marcus and Pella are dead.
I have to protect my family.
They're all I have.
I understand your concern
but this is a police matter now.
We're gonna deal
with the kidnapper from here on out.
No. No, I'm not gonna have their
blood on my hands, okay?
Hard to argue with that.
You are not leaving this house
with that phone.
Fine. I'll stay.
But nobody's touching my phone.
Mm. Good luck with that.
Mr. Goodwin.
Mr. Goodwin, open up.
Open the door.
"I'm c... I'm calling my lawyer.
I'm not talking until he gets here."
Okay, we will break down this door
if we are forced to.
- I said, open up!
- Lisbon?
Brenda.
What are you doing here?
Is there a PR issue?
Can I speak with you?
Teresa, you can't break down that door.
I need to access his email
and his phone.
Breaking down the door
is not my first option
but I don't have time to pull a warrant.
That may be the case
but Director Bertram is very concerned
about the way we handle this one.
We need to be very gentle
with the Goodwin family.
- We'll discuss this later.
- No, we can't.
Do you see those press vans pulling up?
Marcus Goodwin is an important
advisor for the Pentagon.
His disappearance is
a national security issue.
If we don't get him and his wife back
do you know what happens?
- We're gonna get him back.
- Yes, I'm sure that we will.
But if we don't, and we treat Isaac badly
he's gonna kill us in the media.
Kill us.
You've got your problems, I've got mine.
Well, then I'm sorry to do this
to you, Teresa.
What are you doing?
Calling Director Bertram.
Fine. Uh, you win.
Sorry.
I'll tell if you steal one.
Uh, may I see that?
Whoa. That's odd.
What?
They drank a 1964
Lafite Rothschild with a pizza.
So?
Well, these people are wine snobs.
They have varietal specific stemware.
They should know better.
Did you happen to see a dog anywhere?
No.
Howard?
Where are you, boy?
Isaac?
I talked it over with my boss
and you're right.
You should be the one
to deal with the kidnapper.
Nobody's gonna take your phone.
I feel bad that you're you in there.
- Isaac?
- "Lawyer."
Hey, Howard. Come on.
Oh, hey. Howard.
How you doing?
Found old Howard lounging by my pool.
He's a sneaky one.
- Does he get out a lot?
- No, but he tries.
Marcus and Pella do a pretty good job
of keeping him on the property.
- I bet it was that gate, wasn't it?
- Oh, why do you say that?
Well, it's got a funny latch on it.
And it's hard to close
if you're not used to it.
Hm.
Something about the Goodwins, huh?
Yeah. Uh, do you think you
could watch Howard for me?
- Oh, not at all.
- I really appreciate it. Thank you.
See you, Howard.
Jane!
Just a minute!
What are you doing?
Lisbon. I got something.
I need to get in touch with Isaac's lawyer.
What, you still can't get him out of there?
You can? Good luck.
Yo, Isaac.
I got something to tell you.
Marcus and Pella weren't kidnapped.
Somebody else was.
- What? Who?
- Well, I don't know, but...
Unlike Marcus and Pella, they don't know
their Bordeaux from cheap table plonk.
And they listen to Country, not Opera.
And unfortunately, they let Howard out.
What did you say?
- Who the hell is Howard?
- Dog.
- Isaac? What's going on here?
- Marcus.
Well... We thought you were kidnapped.
Well, not all of us.
Uh, we've been hiking all weekend.
It was a last-minute trip.
We were at our place in the mountains.
There's no phone. No cell reception.
We had no idea.
- Who was staying at the house?
- Gary and Sloan Dietz.
We've been best friends
with them for years.
Marcus and Gary were
roommates at Cal-Tech.
This is insane.
- Do you have a photo of the couple?
- Um, yeah.
They were, uh, house sitting.
We have a dog.
Oh, great dog, by the way.
He's, uh, with the neighbor.
So the kidnapper has Gary and Sloan
but he sent Isaac an email
saying that he has us?
We think that maybe they took
the wrong couple by mistake.
Well, obviously.
But by now the kidnappers must've figured
out that they took the wrong people, so...
I mean, what happens to Gary and Sloan?
Are they gonna get killed?
Don't even say that.
- I'm just being realistic.
- Isaac, shut up.
Isaac's always been
the family scourge, hasn't he?
- Stubborn, arrogant, insensitive.
- Hey, enough.
Someone's trying to video conference.
It could be the kidnapper.
I'm sending the feed to the laptop.
- Oh, my God.
- "Who are you? Where's Isaac?"
I'm with the police.
You're dealing with us now.
"I said no police."
Things have changed.
"So you've figured out
I took the wrong people."
"I'm guessing Marcus and Pella are there?"
They're right here.
"Good.
Because I have a question for them."
"Do you wanna see your
friends alive again?"
Yes. Yes, we'll do anything.
"Five million dollars
in non-sequential bills."
"You have 24 hours to get it.
If you don't, your friends die."
"I'll contact you in the morning
with instructions for delivery."
Uh, quick question before you go.
Uh, kidnapping Gary and Sloan wasn't
a mistake, was it?
"What are you talking about?"
Kidnapping Gary and Sloan was
always the plan, wasn't it?
"No."
You see, I think you did your homework.
You wanted Marcus' money
but if you kidnapped him
then you would have had
to deal with Isaac.
Bullheaded guy like that, you'd be
lucky to get twenty bucks out of him.
"Who is this?"
Huh? But you did take Gary and Sloan
but you sent an email saying
you had Marcus and Pella.
That way Marcus thinks
he's supposed to be taken.
He feels wracked with guilt.
And the nice guy that he is, he doesn't
think twice about dropping a few mil.
You know him very well.
"Shut up."
"I want the five million or they die."
Oh, you're clever enough to know
that that's not gonna happen.
You're selling beer now, not champagne.
No one's gonna pay five million dollars.
Three, maybe.
- "It's five."
- Three's a better number.
"Then people start dying."
What did you do?
He'll call back.
Jane?
Jane.
- Don't worry. He'll call back.
- Then why do you look worried?
I'm not.
No luck tracing the email to Isaac
or the video conference.
Have you heard from Cho and Rigsby?
They're still going through
the security camera footage.
Told you.
- "Four million. Final offer."
- Yeah, that's fine.
- All right. Four million.
- "I'll contact you in the morning."
Okay.
Isaac, let's get the money together.
Are you kidding?
Look, just because you guys
feel guilty
doesn't mean you should give away
millions of dollars here.
Gary's a high school physics teacher.
Sloan's a paralegal.
They don't have this kind of cash.
It's not your fault that Gary
isn't successful.
- This is not your problem.
- Yeah, it is. Okay?
Gary's family.
Now get the money.
Oh. You don't have it, do you?
What?
Of course he's got it.
It's complicated.
Look, the market has been unpredictable.
And I have done the best
that I can possibly do
but there have been
significant reversals.
I've done my best, but most of it
is tied up in illiquid securities.
But the books don't say that.
Look, if you wanna get
the four million dollars
then you're gonna have to start
selling off assets.
And who knows how long
that's gonna take.
I'm sorry, Marcus. I really am.
You son of a bitch.
I think you guys should just talk
amongst yourselves for a while.
I'm out of here.
- You're leaving?
- Yes. I have a driver coming in.
Let me know how it goes.
Will you please eat that like a human
being and not a sea lion?
Hold on.
I think I got something.
Going pretty fast.
Where was that taken?
A security camera three blocks
away from the Goodwin house.
Could be our guy in the van.
There's no license plate.
And only 98000 white vans
registered in Northern California.
Check for abandoned white vans.
Looks like a Dodge.
See if that narrows it.
Fifty-six.
But one of them was found six miles from
the Goodwin house just a few hours ago.
Reported stolen last week.
Maybe the owner saw something.
Let's check it out.
Okay.
This is Lorelei Martins.
She's a confederate
of the serial killer, Red John.
Nineteen days ago, she disappeared
from Sacramento County Jail.
Someone drove her out.
Was it you?
- You oughta check the log.
- I have.
You realize I transport dozens
of prisoners every day.
Sure.
Never seen her in my life.
- You're lying.
- Excuse me?
- I don't have to listen to this.
Sit, no... Sit... Please, sit down.
You gonna make me?
Wrong move, Walter. Just stay.
I know, right?
It's like, "Hello?"
"It's your birthday, ho. Cheer up."
I gotta call you back, girl.
I've got some Jehovah Witnesses
or something at the door.
All right.
CBI, ma'am.
Your 2002 white Dodge van was
reported stolen last Wednesday.
Mm-hm.
- Any idea who might've taken it?
- Uh, no?
If I did, dude would be rotting
in a cell about now.
Is that 70 inches? Expensive.
Mom's got glaucoma.
Your van, it was ten years old
and in bad condition.
It's an odd vehicle to steal, isn't it?
And suddenly you have
the cash to buy a new TV.
Listen, the longer you lie to us
the worse it's gonna be.
All right, fine.
It wasn't stolen. I sold it.
To who?
Don't know.
Dude ain't give me his name.
Didn't want me to sign
over the title either.
But he gave me a couple thousand
extra, so I was like... All right.
So why'd you report it stolen?
I didn't know what he was gonna do
with that van, and it was still in my name.
Mm-hm.
Didn't want it coming back on me.
You need to come work
with our sketch artist.
See if we can get a likeness of this man.
If I help, can I keep the TV?
Let's go.
I was just asking. Ugh.
Ma, I'm going.
We've scraped together everything that
we can, and we're still a million short.
Isaac's trying to sell some of our assets
but even if he does, the money's
not gonna get here in time.
We're just... We're at a loss.
Even if by some miracle
we do get this money today
how do we know that he's not still
gonna kill Gary and Sloan?
Honestly, you never do.
That has to be a risk
you're willing to take.
No, we're willing.
Of course we're willing.
This is it.
"Gary and Sloan are still alive.
How long, is up to you."
- "Is the money ready?"
- Pella and Marcus need more time.
"You're lying."
They have every intention
of paying the money.
"Stop lying to me, bitch.
I know they have it."
Hey, just for that, you're not gonna
see a dime. Not until you do as I say.
- "What?"
- Shut your mouth and you listen to me.
I need to know you're not gonna kill
them after you get the cash.
So this is what you're gonna do.
You're gonna release one hostage
in exactly one hour.
- Consider it a show of good faith.
- "Wait, I..."
You heard me! One hostage in one hour.
And if you don't, don't bother calling back.
What?
- Boy, I think that was pretty convincing.
- You might've just gotten them killed.
No video conference. Just a call.
Hello?
This is Sloan Dietz.
I was told to call this number.
- Yeah?
- Please, help me.
I'm sorry. I don't know anything.
I'm not sure where he brought us.
We... we were blindfolded.
Did you hear any distinctive
noises on the trip?
Airplanes? Trains?
I don't know. I don't... I don't remember.
Everything happened so fast. I'm sorry.
It's fine.
Take a look at this.
It's from a description of the kidnapper.
Do you recognize him?
No, uh... He never let us see his face.
I'm not being very helpful at all.
I'm so sorry.
Why don't we take a break?
We need to find the money
to get Gary back.
That's what this comes down to.
Well, what do you think, Isaac?
It's not gonna happen this fast.
I'm doing everything that I can, but...
Not everything. You could chip in.
I want to. But a million dollars? That's...
That's almost everything that I have.
Please, Isaac.
Sloan, don't think that
I don't feel for you. I do.
I will pay you back.
Look, I know
how ridiculous that sounds
but I swear, trust me, I will work every
day for the rest of my life.
I swear it.
It's okay, Sloan.
I'll pay you back, Isaac.
You know I'm good for it.
Please.
Don't let him die.
We have the money.
"Good."
"Now listen carefully."
"I want it tomorrow, ten a.m.
at the Village Plaza."
"There's a table by the pretzel cart.
The wife will bring it there."
Sloan?
That's not gonna happen.
"I won't let you have some undercover
cop bring the money."
"This is non-negotiable."
"Don't push me."
When can we get proof of life?
"Nine AM."
"If you disrupt the exchange, or if
I see a cop anywhere near that mall..."
I promise Gary is a dead man.
Who's gonna tell Sloan?
Well, I think you guys
can handle it from here.
Hey. You never told me
what happened with the driver.
Yeah, it's must've, uh...
slipped my mind.
Excuse me.
He knows something, doesn't he?
Jane, let me help you.
Thank you.
"Harder. Harder."
I don't know if I can
go through with this.
We have the money ready for you.
All you have to do is hand it over.
Piece of cake.
I'll be outside if you need me, okay?
- Hey, baby.
- "Hey."
So? How'd it go?
They don't have a clue.
You're sure they don't suspect you?
Hundred percent.
What are you so nervous
about, Vince?
We never meant for you
to get released this early.
And we never meant to kill that guard.
We're improvising.
And I don't like that.
It's all gonna work out.
- You all set for tomorrow?
- We're good.
Just bring the money down to the storage
basement, and I'll get it out of there.
You're forgetting the last part.
I don't wanna kill him.
I know you don't.
Put him on for me.
I wanna say goodbye.
Sloan. Please.
For God's sake, you don't
have to do this.
You could be a little more
convincing, Gary.
- What did I ever do to you?
- You still don't understand, do you?
"But that's always been
your problem, Gary."
You wasted ten years of my life.
You dragged me down with you.
Never again.
- Sloan, please.
- Goodbye, Gary.
Sloan, wait.
It's a very sensitive mic.
We'll be able to communicate
the whole time.
You'll hear us, we'll hear you.
Test, one-two.
- Is that coming through?
- Yes. Yes.
And we'll be nearby, in case anything
goes wrong.
We won't be seen.
It'll just be our team, okay?
- How are you doing, Sloan?
- Hanging in.
We've got ten minutes till the pickup.
Hang in there.
Boss, what's happening?
We're just sitting tight.
Nothing's going on.
"Wait a minute."
"I see somebody who fits
a description of the kidnapper."
"It may be early, but I'm gonna get
a closer look, see if it's him."
"It's definitely the kidnapper."
- "I'm going in."
- Okay, I'm coming.
"I'm on my way."
- You can't arrest him.
- We can't risk him getting away.
- What about Gary?
- We'll do everything we can, but...
"He spotted me."
- "Shots fired."
- "I'm almost there."
"I've been hit."
- Stay here.
- "I've been shot."
Move in! I need... I need rescue. Please!
- Okay, just bring it down...
- Hurry!
Rigsby, car.
It was a little over the top, okay?
He's trying to get away!
And cue gunshots.
Returning fire.
- And he's hit.
- "The kidnapper's down."
"He's still alive."
"We got him."
That's good.
You don't criticize his performance?
Just mine?
He was good. You?
I've got her. She's on the exterior.
She's on the move.
Heading toward the west entrance.
Going down the escalators.
She just went into the back corridor. B-7.
Damn it.
She just went into a dead zone.
She knew exactly where to go.
South end of the mall. Move in now.
Got it. Move.
The kidnapper must've planted
her change of clothes here.
She had an escape plan the whole time.
She knew things might go bad.
There's only one number on the phone.
Must be Sloan's accomplice.
If we can trace his phone's
location, we can find him.
Do it.
Van Pelt. Trace this number for me.
I got it.
The kidnapper's still in the mall.
I t looks like he's in the storage basement.
Freeze. Freeze!
Don't move! Don't move!
Down on the ground now. Get down!
Hands behind your back.
All right, stand up.
Tell me where Gary is.
Screw you.
We know Sloan's behind this.
You were just her puppet.
Now, we may be able to go a little
easier on you
but not unless you help us right now.
It's over.
Don't be stupid.
He's in a warehouse.
Nine North Citrus Avenue.
Don't move.
Let me see your hands.
Hands behind your back.
How did you...
Get her out of here.
Gary!
Oh, my God. I can't believe it.
Thank you so much.
- You all right?
- Yeah. No, I'm okay.
It's so good to see you.
- So we got Sloan.
- Mm.
How did we know she was one
of the kidnappers?
When we were negotiating
Vince had to hang up
and talk to somebody before
making a counter-offer.
We figured that person
was the mastermind
and somebody who knew
the Goodwins well.
So Jane asked Vince to release
a hostage.
Whoever he released had to have
been his collaborator.
- Amazing. Where is Jane?
- On a personal errand.
Shoot. A few reporters
wanted to interview him.
This is turning into a pretty big story.
I could do it.
Yeah, that's okay. I got it.
Welcome home.
What the hell are you doing here?
Sorry, I... I didn't mean to alarm you.
Get out of my house.
I will in a moment.
But first we need to talk.
- It's... It's important.
- I've got nothing to say to you.
Then have a drink and listen.
Please.
I think you're in trouble, Walter.
Wrong.
I'm here to help you.
Help me?
You don't even know me.
I know that you still love your wife
even though she broke your heart.
I know that you're very lonely.
I know you're tormented by sexual desires
that make you feel ashamed of.
I know you like scotch.
Get out.
I'm telling you this so that you know
that it's pointless lying to me.
The FBI made you move Lorelei because
they had leverage over you, right?
I said get out.
They had leverage over you
because of a crime you committed.
No.
That's as good as a yes, Walter.
You raped a woman, didn't you?
No.
An inmate.
The FBI took that information
and they blackmailed you.
And made you take
Lorelei on a mystery tour.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
You say that, but what you're thinking is
"How does he know this?"
"How can he read my mind."
And no, hitting me won't do you any good.
You don't understand.
I... I couldn't help myself.
I'm so sorry.
We all have our weaknesses, Walter.
Who contacted you?
A man called me on the phone.
I never saw him.
Name?
Nemo.
Said his name was FBI Agent Nemo.
Oh, that's cute.
Latin for nobody.
Where did you take Lorelei?
I promise, I'll never touch
another inmate. Never, I swear.
I believe you, Walter.
Where did you take Lorelei?
Look at me, Walter.
You have a chance to make this right.
Where did you take Lorelei?
Okay. I'll tell you.
He's all yours.